[Money for Nothing
by Dire Straits
♪ MTV...
What the hell are you doing?
Packing.
You know, I can see that.
But, where are you going?
I don't know.
Livingston for a few days
while I figure it out.
Why?
Because I sacrificed
his little lamb.
What the hell does
that mean, Beth?
Doesn't matter.
He doesn't want me here.
And if I've learned
anything about life, it is
not to be somewhere
where you aren't wanted.
Mm-hmm, well, guess what?
You're wanted.
Not by him.
- Beth?
- Yeah.
You just put that down for...
Beth?
Just stop.
I...
I thought we made
a promise to each other.
Hey...
You can run away and then wander
back in a few years
and think that
everything's gonna be the same,
but it won't.
I mean, he might be gone.
Shit, this ranch
might be gone.
And when it's gone,
baby, I'm gone.
You break your promise to me...
and it stays broken.
I'm sorry. I didn't know
what she meant to you.
It's not what she means to me,
honey, it's...
It's what's right.
What's decent.
No rules with our enemies,
but she isn't an enemy.
Well, that's an argument
for another time.
But... your ranch, your rules.
I fight how you say fight.
I'd like to stay.
This is your home.
You don't need
my permission to live here.
For me, I do.
Then you have it.
Thank you.
Beth...
Yeah?
I love you, okay?
That never changes.
Morning, Mama.
Hey, baby.
You can't call me that.
Why not?
Because it's not true.
I just thought 'cause I don't
have one, you could be it.
You been acting like it.
I've been acting like your
friend, which is what I am.
You lost your mother, kid.
You don't get another.
I lost mine.
Same goes for me.
And I'm nobody's mother. Ever.
You got it?
Crying doesn't help.
Never does.
You were in prison?
Yeah.
Explain that to me.
Explain prison.
What part?
Could you have visitors?
I didn't have any,
but I guess I could have.
Wives?
Girlfriends, they can visit?
Yeah.
Can they do more?
Like, conjugals?
Yeah, you can do that.
You just got to
reserve a room.
One last question...
how do I get a weapon in?
What kind of weapon?
One that doesn't
look like a weapon.
Them hair pins
are pretty good.
Just got to give the guards
something else to look at...
I reckon they wouldn't be
too concerned about your hair.
Thank you.
What in the fuck
was that about, Walker?
She was asking me
about prison.
Prison?
Yeah. Think she wants
to kill somebody.
Whatever she told you,
you don't tell anybody else.
You understand me?
Yeah, I got that.
Hey.
What are you doing?
My last act before
the kinder, gentler me appears.
I don't need you getting
in trouble, Beth,
or hurt or killed.
If you need something
taken care of
you tell me
and I'll take care of it.
I know, baby.
But this one's just for me.
Okay?
I love you.
All right, let's not
overbet the pot here.
40.
Shit.
Betting like
you made the flush.
That's because
I did make the flush.
If you made the flush
you would be acting
like you didn't
make the flush.
You're just trying to put me
off of my flush.
That is
absolutely ass backwards.
I am begging you
to match the pot.
Begging you.
Daddy needs a new pair of shoes.
Let me see.
Let me see your face.
You are so full of shit again.
You are bluffing.
If he's bluffing
why are you folding?
I ain't got shit either.
I am bluffing.
- You know what? I'm going to raise you 40...
- Woo!
'cause you're lying
and that's not nice.
Go, girl!
Let's put the man
to a decision.
I've already made my decision.
I'm all in.
Me too.
Turn 'em over.
- Let's see 'em.
- Bye.
Oh!
Ace, king, seven, Jack.
Okay, so you weren't lying...
All right.
But, gee, and all I have
is this Ace and Seven.
Woo!
She went and dry fucked 'em
right there, didn't she?
Yes, she did.
Didn't you three
girls get fired?
He didn't say
we couldn't come back.
That's exactly what it means
when you get fired,
it means you are not supposed
to come back ever.
So, if I get
fired from McDonald's,
I can't ever go
back to McDonald's
and get something to eat?
- She's got a point.
She'd have a point
if we sold hamburgers, Lloyd.
Technically, we kind of
do make hamburgers.
- Hey!
- Well, well, well...
It's the Texican.
- Look who it is?
- How y'all doing?
Everyone's great, Jimmy.
Everyone except for Ryan.
- Fuck you.
You can always do one of
those payday loans.
You can see things haven't
changed here. Pull up a chair.
Actually, uh...
I'm gonna need two chairs.
- Why?
- Oh.
Ruh roh.
Oh, that's gonna go over
like a fart in church.
Everyone, this is Emily.
She's a vet down the Sixes.
And, uh...
She's my fiancée.
Oh, shit.
No, no, no no!
No fighting!
Let them fight,
they don't even work here.
- Kick her fucking ass!
- Just let them fight.
- Emily! Emily! Emily!
- Oh!
- I got $20 on Texas.
- Yeah!
No, no, no, no!
Fucking barrel racers.
- That's enough, come on!
- Fuck you!
Fuck!
Whoa. Whoa.
- Frickin' mess!
- Well, shit!
Always good to exercise
after a long drive.
What're the chances
there's some whiskey in here?
- Chances are good.
Nice hook.
Looks like this one's free.
It is now.
- What's the game?
- Whatever you want it to be.
Let me fucking go!
How fucking dare
you bring her here?
How was I supposed
to know you're going to be here?
You don't fucking work here!
You said you were
done with me.
And now it's the
other way around.
Yeah.
God. You didn't fight.
Not even a little.
I took you at your word.
You said that if I left
we were through. I left.
And I met her.
And I...
And I fell in love.
And when I had to leave there
and come back here
she chose an option that
she chose to come with me.
So, it's my fault.
It's nobody's fault.
I had a lot of growing up to do.
I wish that I'd done it before
you and I met, but I didn't.
Okay.
Just forget everything that's
happened before right now.
All right. Choose.
Choose.
Her or me.
- Mia...
- Choose!
Take me home, Laramie.
I'm sorry, sir.
I didn't see you there.
Walked down to see the horse.
Didn't seem
like a conversation
I wanted to interrupt.
Well, to be honest, I wouldn't
have minded the interruption.
Yeah.
It, uh...
It had that look.
Come on.
Come show me the horse.
You want me to take
that blanket off him?
Nah.
You know, I've never figured
out a way to look at one
and know if it had
a shred of talent or heart.
But if you look
at all this horse has done,
and all his babies have done...
I guess that's what
talent and heart looks like.
I see you drove up
here in the four sixes truck.
Yes, sir.
My fiancee'll drive it back
with her when she goes.
Fiancée.
Yes, sir.
Oh.
Now the fiancee's gonna
drive back
and you're not going with her?
I'm going to work off
what I owe you.
Then we'll figure it out.
So the wedding's gonna
be in, what, 75 years?
I broke my word to you once.
Almost did it again
to stay with her.
No, I'm going to pay you
what I owe.
Texas was good for you.
Yes, sir, I think it was.
Only person you owe
is yourself, Jim.
You don't owe me a thing.
Thank you, sir.
No matter what you decide,
or...
how it works out, you
always have a place right here.
You're not doing
what he asked.
He said pray for a vision.
But I don't see you praying.
So... What are you doing here?
You need help?
Let me in.
I can help you.
I can't.
Just open the doors.
They told me not to.
I'm your brother.
Let me help you.
They won't let me.
Let me in, you fucking child!
Look at me!
This is your vision!
This is your destiny!
Baby, shh.
It's just a dream.
Shhhh.
Hey, start looking
for that son of a bitch!
He might be laid up
in them trees
or that deep grass over there.
I got him.
You weren't in
Texas that long.
Let him try, Lloyd,
let him try.
Go on, Jimmy.
He didn't run like
he has pneumonia, did he?
No, Jimmy.
He sure didn't.
Let him go.
You toss one hell
of a loop, Jimmy.
Yeah, you may make
a team roper yet.
Spend enough time roping
during the day
I don't have to go waste my
nights doing it.
That's like a dentist
going home
and looking at
pictures of teeth.
Whatever you say, Tex.
I'll be damned. Look who went
off and become a cowboy.
Yeah, it seems that way,
doesn't it, Lloyd?
Any more in here?
I don't believe so.
Let's just do a little
once-over though, yeah?
Okay.
When people come here,
they expect their opponents
to be a bunch of rednecks.
People of the land,
I guess you could say...
They don't expect you.
They don't expect a fight.
That's why you have been
such an effective
nuisance for so long.
I, however, was aware
of just what a huge problem
you could be.
I was prepared...
I gave you enough rope
to hang yourself,
and oh boy did you
fucking hang yourself.
You have violated everything
from the terms of your
contract to your NDA.
You have committed
corporate espionage.
I don't know
anything about that.
Look at the ease
with which you lie.
Do you think I don't know
anyone at the Times?
We own that fucking building!
What do you
suppose we'll find
when I subpoena the little
hippie's call records?
And the reporters.
Good luck with that.
First Amendment and all...
I manage the largest private
fund in the world.
And you know what you've done?
You've made it personal for me.
I don't care how much we spend,
or how long it takes,
I'm gonna put a public restroom
where your fucking house is.
I'm gonna chop down every tree,
and dam every creek.
I am going to rape
your fucking ranch to death.
And you, you little bitch,
are going to prison.
Needless to say, you're fired.
Gonna be late for my date.
See ya, Cal.
You've been as
uninteresting as I expected.
Ma'am?
John Dutton here to see you.
Send him in.
Thank you.
John.
Hello, Mitch.
You walk pretty good
for a man who got shot.
I play eighteen holes,
I can't walk for a month.
Well, it's been
a few months now.
I stand corrected.
Have a seat.
What can I do for you?
I wanna talk about
this Summer Higgins case.
You know her?
Little bit.
From what I know
she's not a criminal.
Overly passionate, maybe...
John, she's an
environmental terrorist.
Forty-two arrests
in a dozen states.
I've put many an
armed robber in prison,
they're equally as passionate
about their position.
But because these people
think that their cause
has some moral high ground
they think the laws
don't apply to them.
But the laws
they break are still broken.
An officer was still assaulted,
land was still vandalized,
and property was
still destroyed.
My obligation is
to the rule of law,
which is eroding everywhere.
Not here.
Not on my watch.
So you're willing
to send her to prison
for the rest of her life?
I instructed council on both
sides to ignore her motivation,
focus on the damage,
and bring me a plea
agreement with some weight.
But you speaking
on her behalf has weight too,
and I'll take it
into consideration.
I appreciate it, Mitch.
John,
she is going to prison.
Only thing to debate
is how long.
What the fuck is this?
It's your conjugal.
I don't have
a fucking conjugal.
We can take you back
to your cell if you want.
Let me figure this out.
Well, this place
is depressing as hell.
It's prison.
It's all depressing.
I'd love to shine
a blue light on that couch.
Who are you?
I'm one of the people
you tried to kill.
I don't know you
to want to kill you.
You tried to kill my father.
And my brother.
You're a Dutton.
Bingo.
Look, like I told the other
the order came in.
I sent it out.
For me, it's just business.
What other guy?
The suit.
The lawyer.
The one in the papers.
This lawyer?
That's the one.
You know you're going
to die here, right?
Yep.
When you're old and weak
and you can barely take a piss
and it's been so long since
you had any decent food
that you actually look forward
to the fish fry on Fridays
and you're waiting to die
and everyone that you've known
is gone or forgotten you,
you will realize...
they have you perfectly trained.
Trained to stand up,
trained to sit down,
trained to line up,
trained to sleep.
And you will realize
that your time on this planet
has been an utter waste
and failure.
And you will know
in your heart
that this world would have been
a better place without you.
And then you'll
remember me telling you.
You know, life isn't
a longevity contest.
what good you can get from life,
what good you can give it.
And your life is already over.
You're just waiting to die.
I hope you wait
'til you're a hundred.
Hey, sweet tits,
you ain't ropin'?
We're on cooler patrol.
Come on, don't be intimidated.
You gotta come up here,
an rope with mama.
Yeah, get out there
and rope with mama,
this cooler's gonna be
safe with me.
That joke's getting old.
- Not even a little.
- No, it's super old.
They age like fine wine.
There's turtles that live
two hundred and fifty years.
Your jokes are older...
Are you two a couple?
♪ In this road of loneliness
Hey, go fucking
get 'em, baby!
You do realize that this
isn't an actual rodeo, right?
Yeah, we're just, you know,
playing, it's just for fun.
Sure, sure, sure.
Next up, old timers.
Old timers?
Hell, I'm only thirty six.
36? I thought you were fifty.
You motherfuckers drink
that cooler dry
and I'm gonna
rope your ass next.
- Lloyd, you ready?
- I'm ready, Jake.
♪ Well, my momma has a nice way
telling me I look like hell..♪
Hup, hup!
- Woo!
- ♪ I guess it's from
the alcohol ♪
♪ I guess I might as well
How's that for an old fart?
Does it hurt your arthritis
or anything
when you
swing that rope around?
All right, Jimmy.
I've seen you head.
Let's see if you can heel.
- Come on.
- Good job, good job.
♪ Damn you, devil,
endless road and loneliness ♪
- You good, Jimmy?
- Yes, sir.
All right.
- Woo.
- Damn.
Look at Ol' Jimmy rope.
I don't understand
the world anymore.
He's a hand, ain't he?
Dogs are purring.
Cats are barking.
I don't understand anything.
You two are fucking crazy,
you know that?
Like bananas in the brain.
A barrel racer girl
just called us crazy.
Yeah, I know.
I just don't know
how to respond.
Caught one for you.
How the fuck you'd hurt your
knee roping a steer?
I didn't hurt it
roping the steers.
I hurt it fucking your mother
the other night.
Fuck you, first Jimmy,
now you're all fucked up.
Gittin' fucked
up her pee-hole.
I've been ringing this
fucking thing for an hour!
Come join us, baby!
- Sorry, Gator.
- Calm down, Gator.
Have some fucking whiskey.
We're coming.
Come on, drink up.
Bring the whiskey out here!
You happy?
I know who I am now.
Or at least what I want to do.
And who I want to do it with.
What do you want to do?
String together a whole
lifetime of days like today.
It's hard to do.
No.
No, it's hard to do here.
This job's hard enough
without having to fight
the whole world
for the right to do it.
Texas...
I'm not fighting the neighbor
to do my job
because he's got
the same job.
And so does his neighbor.
It's just cattle and cowboys
all the way to the horizon.
You're going back to Texas,
ain't you?
I'm not much of a fighter.
I might make a cowboy yet.
Hell, Jimmy,
You're a cowboy already.
Good luck.
Did you try calling her?
Yeah, she didn't answer.
Should I be worried?
Think I'm worried
enough for both of us.
Sorry I'm late.
So, before dinner I've got a
little business to take care of.
Everybody outside.
What business, honey?
Everybody out, come on!
Outside.
Come on, let's go.
Give me a hand, would ya?
Beth...
What the hell
are you doing?
There's something
that I gotta do tomorrow, Dad,
and I want to be a
married woman when I do it.
Honey, let's do this right.
Let me plan--
I don't give a shit
about the wedding, Dad.
I just care about the marriage.
Sweetheart, that's a priest.
We aren't fucking Catholic.
I don't care.
He can sign the thing, right?
That's all that matters...
We're getting married.
You okay with this?
Beth, you are so
fucking crazy.
I thought you wanted to find
a place that was just ours.
I do.
We will take that ride,
I promise.
Sweetheart, if it makes
you happy, I'm happy.
There's two things
I gotta grab real quick.
Just give me one second,
all right?
Be right back.
Look, I'm just sayin'
it's not chili.
- It's chili.
- It's got beans in it.
The whole point of chili
is to use up all the shit
you got in you kitchen, you can
put anything you want in it.
No, no, that's stew.
As soon as you put beans
in chili it ain't chili.
Then what the fuck
do they call this in Texas?
They don't call it anything
because it doesn't exist,
it's got beans in it.
They don't eat beans in Texas.
They eat beans all day they
just don't eat them in chili.
So why the fuck does
Texas get to decide
what the fuck goes in chili?
- Because they invented it.
Will y'all shut the fuck up?
I can't eat whatever
the fuck you call it
with you assholes jabbering.
It's good,
it's just not chili.
Lloyd. I need you.
Grab your stuff, will you?
Hey, Rip, will you tell them?
If you put beans in chili,
is it still chili?
Jimmy, shut the fuck up.
Nobody cares about
your goddamn chili.
Yeah, fuck you, Jimmy.
You still owe me a rope.
- Some things just never change.
- But I got to tell you...
This is some damn good chili.
You know, when your mom
makes chili, no beans.
Don't start this shit again.
I feel really bad,
I should have said something
before we came.
I had a very, very brief
relationship
with Colby's mother.
- Here we go!
- It wasn't love.
At least not for me.
I can't speak for her.
It was very, very physical.
Jimmy, I'm gonna
come across this table.
Okay, I'm sorry.
Although it's crazy
you would say that,
that's exactly what
I did with your mom.
- Oh!
- That's it!
I'll break your neck again and
send you back to the hospital!
I'm sorry.
Where we going?
Wedding.
Yours?
Yes, sir.
We ain't had
the bachelor party yet.
Lloyd, we're doing
everything ass backwards, buddy.
You'll be married
and we won't be able to do
any of the shit I'm planning.
- The groom is...
- Big guy, black hat.
So...
You stand here.
And, uh...
You'll take her hand
and walk her here to the...
What would be an altar.
And you are...
I'm the best man.
You stand beside him.
I'm just the stall cleaner.
Stall cleaner
can stay where he is.
And uh, here we go...
Beth...
Beth, you can't wear
that dress at your wedding.
Don't worry, Daddy.
I won't be wearing it long.
Beth, I am not your buddy.
Okay, I'm your...
I'm your father.
So can you factor that in to
our conversations going forward?
Okay.
- Ready?
- Yeah.
I love you.
Honey...
I hope you'll let me do
this again for you.
And do it right.
You can do it
any way you want it.
All right.
Who presents the bride?
Me. I'm--I'm her father.
So normally I would say a few
things about the couple,
but I don't have any
idea who you people are,
so I will just move
onward to the vows.
I, state your name...
I, Rip Wheeler...
Do take...
state her name...
to be my lawful
wedded bride.
Take Beth Dutton to be my
lawful wedded bride.
To have and to hold,
to honor and cherish,
from this day forward,
for better or worse,
for richer or poorer,
in sickness and in health,
until death do us part.
To honor and to love
to cherish through
everything...
until I die.
And then somehow longer, baby.
And now, Miss Dutton,
I, Beth Dutton--
- Fuck yes, I do.
Not yet, uhm...
You do, I suppose.
Are there rings?
No rings.
No, I have one.
Here it is.
What?
It was my mother's ring.
We didn't have much, Beth,
we were poor,
but it's yours.
So am I.
I now pronounce you
husband and wife.
We're married.
Thank you, uh...
Thank you for
doing this, Father.
You're welcome.
And don't worry,
I won't press charges.
Charges?
Sorry, Daddy.
I had to kidnap him.
If I could get a ride
back to my church,
I would appreciate it.
- Hold on. Hold on...
How exactly did she kidnap you?
- Pistol.
- It was just a little one.
Tiny.
- Come on.
Jesus Christ.
Excuse me, Father.
Why don't I take
you home myself?
Damn, that was beautiful.
They all like that?
Hell, kid, ain't none
of 'em like that.
Hey.
Hey!
What do you want from me?
Give me eyes up top.
Knight 33, this is Bravo One.
Be advised,
the beacon is in place.
Thank you for coming.
Did you talk to the judge?
- We talked.
- And?
And he listened.
We're about to find
out how much.
All rise.
The state of Montana
vs. Summer Higgins,
Judge Mitchell
Davis presiding.
Be seated.
At the arraignment, your client
issued a plea of not guilty.
Does your client wish
to change her plea?
She does your honor.
If it please the court,
may council approach?
Council may approach.
They're entering
your plea agreement now.
The judge will ask you
to reverse your plea.
Once you do that, you are
at the mercy of the court.
No, we agreed
to a suspended sentence--
No, your attorneys agreed.
Not the judge.
The judge does
not have to honor it.
What should I do?
Summer, I...
I trust a jury
more than I trust the judge.
Will the defendant
please rise?
Council has presented the court
with a plea agreement.
Are you aware of this agreement?
I am your honor.
Do you wish to change
your plea to guilty?
I do, your honor.
Your plea is changed
to a plea of guilty.
In exchange for your plea
the State is offering
a fifteen year
suspended sentence
and a ten thousand dollar fine.
Are you aware
of this plea offer?
I am, your honor.
When imposing a sentence,
this court must consider
many factors, motive
being one of them.
Many courts in the past
have confused your intentions
with motive.
Your intention, Miss Higgins,
may be to affect policy change,
or bring awareness to issues.
But that is not your motive.
That is not your motive
when you throw rocks
and frozen water bottles.
When you damage private property
and defy lawful orders.
Your motive then
is to destroy and disrupt.
And the result of that is
the erosion of the rule of law.
When courts dismiss
your unlawful acts
they are weakening
the rule of law,
and creating avenues
of opportunity
for people whose sole intent
is theft and violence.
And they prey on the most
vulnerable in our society.
The elderly, the young,
the weak, the poor.
They prey on those least likely
to recover from the attack.
And you, Miss Higgins,
pave the way for them.
I am not swayed by
your college education
and your outreach work
in the community,
in fact the opposite.
You know better.
If you wish to change laws,
run for office or vote for those
who wish to change them as well.
I look at your file
and I see a career criminal,
who has deluded herself
into believing
that she is not
a criminal
because she believes
she is right.
And you may be right,
Miss Higgins,
But that does not exempt
you from the laws
of this state and this nation.
For the two counts of
assault on a peace officer,
I am sentencing you to
fifteen years per offense.
For the charge of defying
a lawful order
I am sentencing you to one year,
for the charge of
reckless endangerment
I am sentencing you
to 18 months,
and for the charge of
criminal trespass,
because you are a
habitual offender,
I am sentencing you to
the maximum of five years.
If you are a model inmate
who treats the rules of prison
with more respect
than you treat our laws,
you will be eligible for
parole in fourteen years.
Bailiff, place the
inmate in custody.
Wait, what?
I'm trying to make
the world a better place
and you're taking my life?
- All rise.
- You're taking away my life?
What's happening?
Summer, look at me.
Look at me.
Stop crying. Okay?
You have a new fight now.
Be ready for it.
We're going to appeal
this in the morning.
Sir, you can't
touch the inmate.
It's her last fucking hug.
Let her have it.
Get your mind right.
It's a long fight
and it starts now.
God damn, Mitch.
Who the fuck do you think you
are marching in this office?
What in the world
was that about?
You will knock before you
enter these chambers
or a bailiff will
drag you out.
You think justice
was served today?
It was harsh, but it was just.
Six months of cleaning
toilets in county jail
is harsh, what you did
was fucking cruel.
It is a necessary
message to send.
What's the message,
fuck with me and I'll put you
in prison 'til
you're too fucking old
to have children?!
Or a goddam career?
Or any life at all?
I followed the letter
of the law.
For fuck's sake.
She's a woman who pushed
a full-grown man.
The law?
You know...
there is a difference between
what's legal and what's just.
Not to me, there isn't.
There is the law and there
is the law and that is it.
Well,
that is the future out there.
That is your voting base.
And you just told them
to go fuck themselves.
You got it backwards, John.
That's what they're telling us.
Give me one of those.
We're losing this place.
And every year
it happens faster.
I know.
I'm trying to stop it.
I don't think it
can be stopped.
Here's what's going to happen.
Charlotte's going
to appeal the sentence.
You will suspend
the felony assaults--
I won't.
You made your point.
Now show some goddam mercy.
Suspend the felony assaults,
reduce the trespass to a year,
you can keep all the others.
She'll be out in eight months.
Yeah, eight months of hell.
So this is it, huh?
The pound of flesh?
It's the right thing to do.
Right barely factors
into it anymore, John.
The cancer of entitlement
is eating everything.
I just snip away
at the symptom.
Have her file
the appeal on Friday.
I don't want it
on the court record
I changed the sentence
after one day.
Friday it is.
I look at my grandchildren...
and I am terrified of the
world we are leaving them.
I honestly have no
idea what this place
will even look like in
a hundred years.
Grass will cover the streets
and weeds will
cover the rooftops.
I don't think we make
it a hundred years.
Then God starts over.
Tries again,
if he's got the stomach for it.
You have a visitor.
I don't have an appointment.
Not an appointment.
A visitor.
I wanted to share
the good news.
He made an honest woman of me.
Congratulations.
Thank you.
What do you want?
I knew it was you.
I'm not playing
this game again.
It's not a game, Jamie.
Hey, on that fancy computer
log onto the Bureau
of Prisons website, would you?
You do have access to that?
I was always
the computer whiz,
let me have a crack at it.
Move over.
Get away from my--
Ow!
I have done everything
I need to do
to never see
this world again, Jamie.
I am prepared.
I will ruin my life today.
And I swear to God
I will fucking kill you
so just sit down
and let me do it.
Auto fill on the passwords?
Good for you, Jamie.
Way to keep the computer
system secure.
Have a look.
If you saw him,
then you know it wasn't me.
That's not what he said.
Well, he's fucking lying.
You saw him in the prison.
I went to see him
at the prison to find out
if my father
was fucking involved.
Was he?
I had no idea. None.
He only admitted it once I held
a fucking gun to his head.
And when he did admit it why
didn't you blow his head off?
He's...
I'll tell you why.
Because deep down in here
it's what you always wanted.
I'm sure he told you that he did
it because he loves you, right?
He loves you, Jamie.
And he wants the best for you,
and all the things you deserve,
but that's just not
the truth, is it?
He just wants what you want.
He wants what everyone
he wants the land.
I tell my father.
He will call the Governor and
he will have you both arrested.
Your spineless,
woman-murdering father
will instantly say
it was your idea.
You know that, right?
He will cut an immunity deal
and he will testify against you.
You will be charged with
attempted murder times three
and will spend the rest
of your life in jail,
which actually
it won't be that long
because you will
probably commit suicide
after your first rape.
now this is a good one.
I tell my husband
what your father did,
and he will kill him.
And then I'll tell my husband...
that you had his child
cut from my belly
and then you had me sterilized,
so he can never have
a family of his own.
And you, no matter
where you hide,
he will find you
and will tear you apart
with his bare fucking hands.
Wouldn't you like to know
which option I picked?
Beth, wait.
Beth, please.
Please, please, please.
Please, please.
There is a third option.
Care to hear it?
You're not real.
Depends on what you
think "real" means.
I don't know you.
You see what
you can understand.
You know me.
You're ready.
Ready for what?
To stand on the cliff.
Come on.
Through the doors.
Close them behind you
or there's no telling
what could be waiting for you
when you get back.
What do you see?
Two paths.
Look down the left one.
Oh, God.
Now look down the right.
Tough choice.
Can you help me make it?
I can help you walk the path.
But you must choose it.
Let's go home.
What did you see?
I saw the end of us.
Come on.
Safe travels, brother.
- See you around, Jake.
- Yes, sir.
My pleasure meeting you.
Just don't ever hit me
like you hit her.
Pleasure was mine.
- See you around, Jimmy.
- See ya.
Now, listen, when you
get back to Texas,
you all start making
fucking babies,
have yourself a hell of a life.
Okay?
You understand a word
of what she just said?
Something about our taxes.
Come here.
Actually, I'm gonna see
you Thanksgiving
at your mom's house.
See ya around, Walker.
You were right
about that chili.
No beans in that shit.
Big old howdy to them
boy in Texas for me.
Yes, sir.
Ma'am.
Come here, Jimmy.
I want you to know
you always have a place here.
All right?
Thank you, sir, I do.
Hey, I'm proud of you.
- Thank you.
- Yeah.
I, uh...
Jimmy, cowboys
don't say goodbye.
They say, "see you later," till
we're in that fucking dirt.
We'll say our goodbyes then.
Got a long drive.
Come on, get out of here.
Let's go.
I'll say this,
she is persistent.
Hey. If you're having
second thoughts,
you're not gonna get
a better chance
than right now to share them.
It's not second thoughts.
It's... guilt maybe.
Regret.
I don't know what to call it.
It's called life.
Most of it hurts.
But that's so when
something feels good
we have a frame of reference.
Where are you going?
I don't know.
Just wander for a bit.
I worry about you alone, though.
You know, those Duttons
are always gonna use
your fear against you.
If I can ever teach you
to be fearless...
Then you will truly have
the world licked.
You'll have everything
you ever wanted.
Hell, you almost
have everything now.
You got the second most powerful
office in the state.
You got a child.
And a woman who believes in you.
And look at this.
This is yours.
Most people...
The best they can hope is to
dream about something like this.
Hell, most people,
they don't even know
something like this exists
to dream about.
I'm 61 years old,
and these last months...
Well, they made all
the sixty years of fucking hell
I endured worth it.
Don't you let those
fucking Duttons deceive you
into thinking you're a bad man.
You're a good man, son.
And I love you.
I love you too, dad.
Stop.
Turn around.
You should have picked
options one or two.
Three's gonna be worse.
Cause you're fucking mine now.
Where have you been?
Keeping my promise.
Which promise is this?
The one where I swore to
destroy anything that hurts you.
Did you?
Speak to me straight, Beth.
Did I lose a son today?
He was never your son, Dad.
He is a disappointment
and my greatest failure
but I...
I raised him and I love him,
as much as I've tried not to.
So just answer the question,
do I still have him?
Yes.
But now you own him, daddy.
I'm going to sleep.
No riding today?
Having trouble
seeing the point today.
There is no point.
It's just fun.
Rip says one day
no one will ride.
Well...
Guess we'd better ride.
- ♪ Put me to peace
in the pines ♪
♪ Don't bother with
those white and yellow lines ♪
Race ya!
- ♪ Take me to the land
where I was dealt my hand ♪
♪ Put me to peace
in the pines ♪
♪ So take this body home
♪ My soul has gone away
♪ And to a better place
♪ And don't let 'em see me
♪ Because you know
I will be crying ♪