[Money For Nothing
by Dire Straits]
♪ MTV... ♪
["The Cowboy in Me"
by Tim McGraw]
- ♪ I don't know why
I act the way I do ♪
♪ Like I ain't got
a single thing to lose ♪
♪ Sometimes I'm my own
worst enemy ♪
♪ I guess that's
just the cowboy in me ♪
♪ I got a life that most
would love to have ♪
♪ Oh, but sometimes I still
wake up fighting mad ♪
♪ At where this road
I'm headed down might lead ♪
♪ I guess that's just
the cowboy in me ♪
♪ The urge to run
The restlessness ♪
♪ The heart of stone
I sometimes get ♪
♪ The things I've done
for foolish pride ♪
♪ The me that's
never satisfied ♪
♪ The face that's in the mirror
when I don't like what I see ♪
♪ I guess that's just
the cowboy in me ♪
♪ Mmm ♪
♪ The urge to run
The restlessness ♪
♪ The heart of stone
I sometimes get ♪
♪ The things I've done
for foolish pride ♪
♪ The me that's
never satisfied ♪
♪ The face that's in the mirror
when I don't like what I see ♪
♪ I guess that's just
the cowboy in me ♪
[lowing]
[music]
[cow bellows]
[phone rings]
- Yes, sir.
All right, Doc, I'll tell him.
Thank you, bye.
Jimmy, Doc wants
you at headquarters.
- Morning, sir.
- Morning.
How's he working out?
- He does his job and shuts
his mouth, for the most part.
- Yeah.
You iron things
out with Beth?
- I'm afraid that ship's
already sailed, sir.
- You'd better start
swimming after it.
She's the reason
you're here, Big Fella.
[music]
- Tate?
Tate?
Tate!
[thunder]
[music]
[chuckles]
- He's sniffing
at those deer tracks.
- Yeah, looks like it.
Here, let me show you something.
See how this front track here
is deeper on the outside there?
- Yeah.
- Means it was looking back
over its left shoulder.
You like to track, huh?
Might have a job for you.
- You should probably name him
before you put him to work.
- I don't know.
"Dog" seems to be working out
just fine.
- You busy today?
- Depends how quick
we find those horses.
If we find 'em at all.
- Ah, so you're working
for miss pouty lips.
- I'm working for the
state of Montana, baby.
Same as every other day.
Fine.
I'll just work cases for
ugly women from here on out.
- Oh, so you think she's pretty?
- Walked right into
that one, Dad.
- [Kayce clears throat]
- We need to name the dog.
Dad just wants
to call her "Dog."
And I think
that sucks pickled ass.
- Hey. Not at the table.
Not anywhere for that matter.
He's your son, I swear.
- I'm not done.
- You're done now.
- You owe me one.
- You're one of those, huh?
- One of what?
- The kind of man who uses
flowers to say "I'm sorry"
because he doesn't have
the balls to say it himself.
I don't want those
fucking things.
[typing]
- I need a ride into town.
Would you give me one?
- What do you need in town?
- This ain't a life:
cleaning up horse shit,
sleeping in a barn...
I don't have any friends.
Not even you.
I'll take my chances
in foster care.
- You're 14, kid.
In four years the world
says that you're a man.
But you're not,
that's what it says.
What becomes of you then?
- I don't know.
- What do you want to become?
What's your dream?
- Don't have any dreams.
- No?
- I'm too busy trying
to figure out
what I'm gonna eat
and where I'm gonna sleep.
Dreams...
- Come here.
You do what I ask
the way I say do it.
You ask questions
when you don't understand.
when you do understand.
Never lie to me.
[music]
Can you make that
promise and keep it?
- I can keep it.
- Shake on it.
- If I don't give you flowers
when I'm sorry,
when do I give 'em?
- You give 'em for
no reason, buddy.
No reason at all.
[music]
- You Jimmy?
- Uh, yes, ma'am..
- Open that for me.
[grunts]
[horse whinnies]
- Is this some kind of
exercise room?
- [chuckles]
Sort of.
All right, get ready.
- Ready for what?
- Put this sleeve over his
penis and hold it.
- What?
- Go, now! Do it!
All right, you got
to hold it there.
Got to get it all.
Hold it there.
[exhales sharply]
[grunting]
Okay, remove it.
[horse neighs]
- I just jacked off a horse.
- Get used to it. We've got
fifteen more to collect.
All right, bring that
into the lab. That door there.
- Just jacked off a horse.
- [Emily chuckles]
[music]
- You like his one?
What does that mean?
Boo!
- He's going to be
a good father.
- That's questionable...
considering who taught him.
- I'm teaching him now.
You know, most people, they
end up making the same mistakes
their parents made
because they were still children
when they had children.
I know I was...
Jamie's endured 40 long years
learning how not to father,
how not to lead.
Hard lessons both,
but he learned them.
- He does seems different.
More like the man
I wanted him to be.
- I have a favor to ask.
- Look, I'm here.
I just...
I'm gonna need some time
before I trust him again.
- Do you trust him to be
a good politician?
- I never doubted him
as a politician.
- How 'bout a governor?
The election's
a ways off, but...
these things need
planning, don't they? I mean...
Relationships beyond district
attorneys and cattlemen.
What kind of relationship
do you have?
Anyway, that's the favor.
- What do you see?
- Well, he looks
like a governor.
- Yes, he does.
- Hello.
Who are you here to see?
- Not here to see a who.
Here to see a thing.
- What thing?
- My office.
- Miss Dutton.
- Winner winner turkey dinner.
- [chuckles]
Right this way.
[phones ringing]
- It's the corner office
right down here.
This is Miss Dutton.
- It's a pleasure to finally...
[sighs]
[knocking]
- All this shit has to go.
- Ma'am?
- I feel like I'm in my
fucking gynecologist's office.
- I'll get the design team to--
- Nope. I'll do it myself.
What's your name?
- Cal.
- Where you from, Cal?
Let me guess: Menlo Park.
- Palo Alto, right next to it.
How'd you guess that?
- I just read
the tea leaves, buddy.
- Ooh, um, there's
no smoking in the, uh...
It's probably fine.
- How long you been
boinking the receptionist?
- Ma'am?
- You know how that's
gonna end, dontcha?
So here's the thing:
I need my assistants
to put all their efforts
into not being pussies, okay?
I do not need them chasing it.
- You want me break up with her?
- I want you to find
another job.
I'm 0 for three
with assistants anyway.
Turns out working for me
is pretty fucking dangerous.
- I'm-I'm...
I'm not really sure
what you're asking.
- I'm not asking
you anything, Cal.
I'm firing you.
Get the fuck out of my office.
I'll get my own coffee.
Hey, Cal?
- Yeah.
- Shut my fucking door.
- Yep.
- All right.
- [sigh]
Not looking too fired, Cal.
- Phase one is white,
phase two, green,
phase three, blue,
phase four, yellow.
Now, you'll notice in phase one,
we lay infrastructure
for all following phases.
- So, you're laying in
roadways, electric, sewage
for all phases in phase one?
- In the long term
it's much more cost effective.
Laying infrastructure
in phases triples the cost.
- Kyle, this makes assumptions
about land ownership
that we can't make.
- Uh, not the time or the place.
This is a design meeting.
- Can I see an ownership
plat over this?
- It's not relevant
at this time.
- Well, if you're building roads
and sewers on land
that you don't own, I'd say
it's pretty fucking relevant.
- Well, I guess we're going
to find out who you're
loyal to, Beth.
- No one mentioned this to me.
- Beth, there are two terminals.
That's fifty-two gates.
You saw the airport design.
- Yes.
- So who did you think
those gates were for?
Hmm?
You said it yourself,
you'd turn it into Park City.
Well, this is Park City.
[cows lowing]
["Don't Go Lookin'"
by Jackson Dean plays]
- Bring to push. Push.
- Ha, ha!
Ha!
- Steer. Steer, steer!
- Show them how it's done,
would you, Scout?
Two of them coming,
both heifers.
- Hey! Hey!
Hey, hey, hey!
- Heifer, heifer, heifer!
[shouting]
- Shh, shh, shh, shh.
Watch Mama here.
[cow lows]
- Let's do it.
- Keep going.
- Boss man's got steer.
Watch your coke.
- Ha!
[shouting]
- Let's snake those
three there, huh?
Hey, hey, hey, hey, hey!
Hey, hey, hey!
- I count 81.
- That's what I got, too, sir.
- My count's 81.
- Yep, 81 it is.
Get 'em to the sale, Rip.
- All right.
- I'll start looking through
the rest of these heifers.
- Thanks, Jack.
How are the boys?
- [chuckles]
They're sore as shit.
I'm gonna give them
a few days to sleep it off.
- Man.
Guess he's done sleeping.
- Mm-hmm.
- Where y'all need me?
- Start sorting heifers.
- Could I have a word, sir?
- She talking to me?
- I believe she said
she wants a word.
- I can't understand a damn word
coming out of her mouth.
Yeah?
- Sir...
Whatever's between Walker
and Lloyd, it's got
nothin' to do with me.
Nothin' to do with
Laramie either.
That was just their excuse.
I was the first one up every
mornin' and the last to be done.
Ask him.
Ask him if anyone
works harder'n me.
- She ain't lying, sir.
- So fight wasn't over you, huh?
- No, sir.
- You just did your job.
- Ever' day.
- Never fooled around
with anyone in the bunkhouse?
- Ain't no one said I couldn't.
- Well, common sense says
you shouldn't
'cause the next fight
will be over you.
- So all that "this is my home
forever" is just talk?
Fucking scarred for life
and it don't mean nothin'?
- You wait over
there a minute.
When the hell did that happen?
- The night that
we took care of that thing
in the forest for ya.
- So, they all wear it.
- Yes, sir.
- And it just slipped your mind
to fucking mention it to me?
- It was the night
before you got hit.
Before everyone got hit.
- Does Kayce know about this?
- Sir, it ain't his fault.
I should've come to you
and talked to you.
- Does he know?
- Yes, sir, he does.
- Jesus.
- Teeter?
Where's your gear at?
- Everything I own's in
the back seat of my truck.
- Go on and grab it.
Put it back in the bunkhouse.
- Thank you.
- Okay. All right.
Sorry... But thank you.
I don't know, do you
need help with... shit?
- Teeter, just go
grab your gear.
And hey.
This means something.
- Yes, sir.
[music]
- [chuckles]
Well, you have an odd
definition of retirement.
- Yeah, well, I never
retired from this.
When Governors
drop by unannounced,
it's either real good or...
real bad.
- You wanna walk with me?
- Oh, boy.
Unannounced and "walk with me."
I'm in for it, aren't I?
- [chuckles]
- [grunts]
- You got it?
- You know I used to just
jump over these.
- [chuckles]
- Oh!
- Okay.
- Well done.
- All right.
[sighs]
- Hit me with it.
- I'm running for Senate.
- [chuckles]
I don't know, Lynelle.
Washington is a different snake.
- Well, I'm a politician, John.
I gotta go where I believe I can
make the biggest difference.
There's no one in Washington
now that's doing that.
They've lost
the art of compromise.
The art of negotiation.
Those are my greatest skills.
- Well, I can think of a few
others you're a master of.
[laughs]
Stewart running for
Governor, then?
- Oh Stewart...
Stewart's sleeping until noon
and then playing 9 holes.
No, Stewart's done.
I think the Governor's office
is ready
for a new generation of leader.
I think Jamie
can take the responsibility--
- Absolutely not.
Absolutely not.
- He's got the name, which
we know is most important.
And he navigated
that Market Equities development
with a skill that not even I
credited him with--
- Skill is not his weakness.
This is his weakness.
It's too much power.
And it isn't his name,
it's mine.
There's other options.
Choose one of them.
- The other options
don't want the Montana
that you and I do.
- Lynelle, there are things...
there are things
about my son you do not know.
Things that make him
unfit for your office.
- He's the devil we know, John.
I'll take the risk.
I mean, unless you want to run
for governor,
then I'll gladly endorse you.
Listen, I just wanted
to tell you all this
so that you weren't finding out
in the newspapers, all right?
- Lynelle...
- I'll take it.
- Take it? Take what?
- Your endorsement.
I'll take it.
- You are going
to run for office
just so that your son
doesn't get it?
- That's how bad he'll be
for everything you and I
worked so hard to protect.
He'll destroy it all.
So if you want a devil
you really know, here he is.
- The press is gonna come
at you hard, John.
- Oh, don't I know it.
- No, I mean, they're gonna
have a lot of questions
about all the
things that you've done
and you're going to have to
find a way to defend them.
- Not gonna defend a thing.
"Damn right, I did it"
is gonna be my campaign slogan.
- [laughs] Oh, geez.
Yeah, that would be your slogan.
- Yeah.
- I... I did not see
this one coming, John.
- Yeah. I'm just...
I'm just full of surprises.
Fuck.
Now I gotta run
for fucking Governor.
[door opens, bell rings]
- Howdy.
- You buying or selling?
[music]
- Trading.
- Trading what?
- One of a kind.
- Wow.
Are you sure?
- Yep.
[music]
[sniffs]
[clears throat]
- I'm Emily, by the way.
- Jimmy.
- Probably should've
introduced myself sooner.
Masturbating stallions sort of
puts us on a first name basis.
- At the very least.
- So, you got a girlfriend?
- Um...
- Fuck, you're one
of six single guys
in this county under thirty.
I dated two of them and the
other three ain't worth a shit.
So... I thought
I'd make my move
before you go on
and get all scooped up.
- Well, umm...
Aside from the wrangler
I'm paired up with
you're the first person
I've seen in, uh...
I actually don't know
how long I've been here.
So... I think my chances
of getting scooped up
are pretty slim.
- Let me buy you dinner.
- No, I can't let you
buy me dinner.
- You've got a girlfriend?
- I don't know.
- Let me buy you dinner.
- No, I can't.
- All right.
- But, uh...
I can buy you dinner.
- All right.
[music]
[laughs]
Crowd: Fur is murder!
Fur is murder!
[chanting continues]
- Of course, you'd shop here.
- My idea of shopping is calling
the sales manager at Gucci
and having her fill
a box the size
of a fucking refrigerator.
You think you're making
a difference? Hmm?
Shaming some
plastic surgeon's wife
out of buying a mink coat today?
What does that save?
Not the mink.
Mink's already dead.
- Not the next mink.
- Yeah, he's dead too.
Fifteen of you standing
in front of a store
yelling at patrons?
That isn't making a difference.
You know, this store is the
caboose of the problem, okay?
The engine of the problem
doesn't know you exist.
This isn't saving
the environment, sweetheart,
this is just inflating your ego
with very little effort.
And when mommy and daddy
get tired of bailing you out
and subsidizing this utter
waste of time, you'll go away.
Meanwhile, the world
continues getting raped.
- What the hell do you know
about protecting
the environment?
- I know they're building
an international airport
15 miles from the national park.
And a ski resort the size
of Crested Butte.
And condos and hotels
and shopping plazas
and restaurants
in the most fragile ecosystem
in North America.
But you know,
you just keep protesting
'til happy-hour, honey.
Then you can sip
your skinny margaritas
and pat yourself on the back
and you'll all get drunk enough
to stanch the stench of
the couscous-eating hippie
you fuck tonight.
- Did you make that up
about the airport?
- Give me your phone.
This one, this is a little
above your pay grade.
This one takes effort.
Strategy.
Sacrifice.
Risk, real risk,
not that bullshit that
you pulled with my brother.
- Why the fuck do they
need another airport?
- They're not in the
business of need, sweetheart.
They're in the business of want.
And they want it because
it's going to make them
a shit-ton of money
and they do not care
how many animals they
have to kill to build it.
- Good dog.
Where'd you get him?
- He just sort of
came with the house.
- What's his name?
- Just been calling him "dog."
- That's what I call mine.
Except I say it in Lakota.
- What's dog in Lakota?
- Sunka.
- I like that.
Mind if I call it Sunka?
- He's your dog. You can
call him whatever you want.
- Sunka!
Looks like he
already knows it.
- When you say it in their
language, they all know it.
[music]
[clicks tongue]
- You can't be here.
- I'm Livestock Commissioner.
He's tribal police.
These horses are property
of the Confederated Tribes
at Broken Rock.
- These are mustangs.
We rounded them up yesterday.
- Mustangs don't have
shoes and brands.
- Son of a bitch.
- Yeah.
- We herd them with
a helicopter.
Don't get that good a look at
them 'til we trailer 'em up.
- Trailer them to go where?
- Auction, I guess.
Some go to the prison.
- These don't.
They're gonna come with us.
- Got proof they're yours?
Stolen you say?
- Yeah, somebody
cut a hole in a fence,
tried to herd 'em
with dirt bikes.
Guess they didn't
want to be herded.
- [laughs]
Damn right they don't.
Pain in the ass
getting them in here.
Took two choppers
and half a damn day.
Look, you know how
the federal government works:
when the wheels are in motion
they're impossible to stop.
We're supposed
to herd them out Friday,
but if you can get them
out before: so be it.
But I don't know
how you're going to do it.
You can't get a truck back here
and you damn sure can't
do it with other horses...
- We'll see what we can
come up with.
- Figure it out by Friday.
- You got any ideas?
- I got an idea.
- Care to share it?
- This idea is hard to explain.
You'll just have to see it.
[crickets]
- No, no, no, no, no, no.
That's not how you do it.
Let me show ya.
You're just tying it
like a knot.
So, here's what you do.
First of all, let's get
it set up right.
So you're going to lay
it flat, right?
And then what you're going
to do is your going to lay
this piece goes down there,
flat, right?
Then these come around twice.
So you go once,
and then twice,
And then you
pull it from here.
And you pull it tight.
Just like that.
Okay?
I don't want you tying a knot
like some fucking team roper.
Now, every piece
of your equipment:
your saddle, your stirrups,
your cinch, your reins,
that's the thing that's
either gonna save you
or it's gonna kill you.
For instance,
if you dally a bull, right,
and you break your rein
off your bridle
it's usually because
either the leather is rotted
or you tied a fucking
square knot... you understand?
[phone vibrates]
Here. I'll loosen it up.
- Hey.
Oh, you know, just watching
some feel-good movie on TV.
Okay.
- Remember to lay
this piece flat, right?
- I gotta go up to the lodge.
- Drive. I don't need you
getting eaten by a bear.
- A bear knows better
than to fuck with me.
- [laughs]
Drive anyways.
- Yes, sir.
- Beautiful.
[music]
[footsteps approaching]
- Need a drink?
You look sad.
- Nah, I--I look lonely.
There's a difference.
You know, my great grandfather
didn't build this place
with the goal
of impressing anyone.
The goal was to...
the goal was to
just make it big enough
that his children
never had to leave.
But you left anyway.
You all did...
- Daddy, I...
He's going to be my husband
and my place is
sleeping beside him.
- As it should be, honey.
It's just I would...
just like my family
under this roof
and he is going
to be a part of my family.
- You want us to move in here?
Ask him.
- I was...
I was hoping you'd ask him.
- Men.
No, Daddy. I'm afraid
you're going to take
an emotional risk
with another man.
And I do mean ask.
If you tell him to jump
off a fucking cliff,
he's jumping off the cliff.
Okay?
So you gotta ask him.
Ask him what he would like...
And then respect
the answer he gives.
- Feel like I'm in [laughs]
fucking couple's therapy.
- If it walks like a duck
and talks like a duck...
- Yeah.
- Goodnight, Daddy.
- Governor Perry's
running for Senate.
She offered
Jamie her endorsement.
- [sighs]
How can such a shrewd
politician be so blind?
- Doesn't matter.
I convinced her to take it back.
[music]
- How?
- Mm.
Because she's giving it to me.
I, uh...
I couldn't think of
anything else to do, so--
Honey, now--
- Dad, now we control
the narrative.
All right,
the first thing you do--
- Honey.
- No, that's the second thing.
The first thing is choosing
any of the fifty fucking things
that Jamie has done that make
him unfit to hold public office,
and then you remove his
fucking ass from the Capitol.
Okay? The second thing--
- Honey. You didn't
let me finish my sentence.
What I was saying is now
I need you to help me
find a way out of...
out of running.
- Not on your life.
- No, Beth, listen to me.
I can't spend
the next four years
of my life in Helena.
- The ranch won't
be here in four years, Dad.
Listen to me, as Governor,
you will have the power
to withhold funds.
You have the power
to reverse state land grants.
You have the power to shut
that fucking airport down.
You have the power to
withhold building applications
and tax exemptions.
You have the power to
withhold gambling licenses.
You have the power to run those
fuckers out of this valley
and then you get to pass a law
so they can never return.
You always tell me
that there is a way,
another way to save
this ranch without selling.
So this is the way.
Tell me there's another.
This is the way.
You know that, don't you?
- Yeah, honey.
I just...
Just wish it wasn't.
- Dad?
- I'm going to help you.
[music]
[sizzle]
[sigh]
[TV audience cheering]
- Come on!
- Come on, come on, come on!
Come on, come on!
- Come on!
Teeter: Yeah, motherfucker!
- Woo!
- That is huge.
- That' a Yellerstone horse?
- For hell's sakes,
the last three
have been Yellowstone horses.
- Look, it's
not Yellerstone.
It's Yellowstone.
- Whatever you say, baby,
just take your pants off.
- Other room.
You can take your pants off
in the other room.
- I don't know why we're
talking about that
when we're watching a horse.
Doesn't even make any sense.
- I gotta get up.
[heavy breathing]
- I don't know shit about 'em.
The guy at the store said
it's a good one.
- Well... hell of a lot better'n
the one you fuckin' tore up.
That's for sure.
- As it should be.
- It sounds nice.
Anything you'd like to hear?
- Hell, I don't know.
Just play me one.
- Hey, boss.
You need a beer.
- Thanks, Jake.
- This one might suit you.
♪ And as I get long gone
Out where that wind blows ♪
♪ The desert sky,
she flies by for miles ♪
♪ Well, as I keep walking a
lot of people keep a-talkin' ♪
♪ About things they've
never seen nor done ♪
♪ Homeless sleep in the park
Sweethearts kiss in the dark ♪
♪ I myself just move
on through town ♪
♪ Moon keeps on shining ♪
♪ And the rich keep on dinin' ♪
♪ And how I love
the highway sun ♪
♪ The stars keep
on fallin' ♪
♪ And the coyotes
are calling ♪
♪ But your mother,
she won't be around ♪
♪ Out to the back ♪
♪ The poet writes
his songs in blood ♪
♪ Where the jukebox
is barking ♪
♪ But I'm just
getting started ♪
♪ Hell, I've yet
to see the light of day ♪
♪ Señoritas lose it
to the Mariachi music ♪
♪ Because New York
is too far away ♪
♪ Out to the back ♪
♪ The poet writes
his songs in blood ♪
- Sir, after lunch
we could bring in
them replacements heifers.
The vet wants to preg-check
them tomorrow.
- Yeah, you go ahead, uh...
You know, the lodge
is where family belongs.
Didn't sound like
a question, did it?
It's a question.
- Right...
Um...
I mean, are you asking us...
To come live up there with you?
- That's what I'm asking.
- We got that stray kid with us
sir, you don't want that.
- Stray kids is fine.
No stray dogs.
- Shit, you know
I don't like dogs.
- Well, then it's settled.
[music]
[exhales]
- You ready?
- Ready as we're gonna get.
Oh, shit.
- Hut, hut, hut, hut, hut!
[hooves approaching]
[whooping]
[ululating]
- Woo-hoo!
[cheering]
- Get yourself some
trail cameras
put 'em somewhere
nobody can see them,
and point 'em at this gate.
Someone tries it again,
we'll know who it was.
- Thank you.
- Yeah.
- Now we go find
who let them out.
- Yeah. That's the plan.
- These are little victories,
in the scheme of things.
You'd be surprised
how much they matter.
We rest the little things
on the large things.
Thank you.
- Happy to help.
- Watch out for that one.
- Why, is she trouble?
- [chuckles]
When they look at you
like that they're all trouble.
- What are you doing?
- I don't know.
- I'm married.
- I noticed.
[music]
Do you believe in love
at first sight?
- Yeah, it's how I felt about
my wife first time I saw her.
- It's how I felt
when I first saw you.
My fucking luck.
- Well, it can't be love.
God wouldn't let you
love something
that can't love you back.
- Yeah, he would.
[knocking]
- Governor's asking for you
to meet her in the press room.
- Is there a press conference
scheduled for today?
- Not scheduled.
- Are we doing this now?
[music]
[murmuring]
- Join us, Jamie.
- Thanks for the flowers.
Meant a whole lot.
- I'm...
I'm surprised you're here.
- We, uh... we wouldn't miss
this for the world.
- Well, as many of you
may have suspected,
I believe that
I can best represent Montana
from the Senate.
The next Governor of
Montana must hold steadfast
to the progress that
we have made,
and yet, never allow
that progress to redefine
what it means
to be a Montanan.
It is my great honor
to introduce you
to my choice as the next
Governor of Montana:
John Dutton.
- John.
- Thank you, Governor.
- [chuckles]
- You don't see it
on your way to work,
in the fields,
or on the mountain.
But there's a war being
waged against our way of life.
They'll tell you all the reasons
why our way of life...
- This is just the beginning.
John: ...are bad
for this country,
bad for our future.
How it's immoral
that you live here,
work here,
grow their food here.
They will tell it so much
you might even start
to believe it yourself.
Question what you do
and who you are.
They'll tell you that
the land's only hope
is for them to
be its steward.
The ugly truth is
they want the land,
and if they get it,
it will never look
like our land again.
That is progress
in today's terms,
so if it's progress you seek,
do not vote for me.
I am the opposite of progress.
I am the wall
that it bashes against,
and I will not be
the one who breaks.